Hello, my name is Dr. Sanya Dutta,
and today we will talk about the cost of fistula surgery.
Fistula, or
fistula, is a tract or tunnel that has
two openings, internal and external, between the anal region and the skin.
When
you pass stool,
pus or blood is discharged through this tract. This can also cause
intense pain and itching. There are
many treatment options
available. Today, we will discuss a common and advanced
option that
uses a laser, called FILAC, or
laser closure of the fistula. This
procedure burns the tract with a laser fiber, which
heals quickly. The cost varies between
40,000 and 55,000 rupees, including the cost of the laser. The
cost varies depending on the hospital, city, and doctor involved. Furthermore, if the
complex procedure fails to drain the pus and
treat the fistula, the cost of the surgery can be adjusted accordingly.  If possible, the doctors
will first drain the pus and then perform
surgery for the fistula
through laser. There is also a combined option
called seton. Seton is a thread that
breaks up your complexion so that the
muscles also start healing simultaneously.
This option can be done very easily and the
recovery is also very quick. The
hospital stay is only for one to two days.
This is also covered in these insurances.
Most of the medical insurance companies
cover it. It is possible that the
coverage as per your policy will
vary. Also,
packages are defined between the hospital and the insurance companies,
so in such cases your
total cost
can go between Rs 60,000 to Rs 1 lakh. For more information on which treatment
option is valid in your case, from which hospital you should get it done,
which doctor
you should consult,
contact Hexa Heal on the number given below.
Thank you
[Sangeet]
You